<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Discovery on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/discovery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Discovery on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/discovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Futurepub10</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/03/16/future-pub-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/03/16/future-pub-10/</guid>
      <description>This week I attended futurepub10, I love these events, I&amp;rsquo;ve been to a bunch, and the format of short talks, and lots of time to catchup with people is just great.
# A new Cartography of Collaboration - Daniel Hook, CEO Digital Science (work with Ian Calvert).
Digital science have produced a report on collaboration, and this talk was covering one of chapters from that.
I was interested to see what the key takeaways are that you can describe in a five minute talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serendipity, a chance encounter (obviously)</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/08/08/serendipity-sames/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/08/08/serendipity-sames/</guid>
      <description>Tonight there was a lovely sameas event on the topic of serendipity. I&amp;rsquo;d stared a blog post about this back in May as a response to to a post that Frank Norman wrote about enablining serendipidous discovery in the digital library. Well, that post kind of lingered, malingered in my drafts directory, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d best get on get something out there, spurred on by the event tonight.
I studied in Edinburgh for a few years, it&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful city, and in the heart of the old town Victoria Street sweeps in a steep curve down to the cowgate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>