<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>london on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/london/</link>
    <description>Recent content in london on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/london/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>aws london summit notes</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2015/04/16/aws-london-summit-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2015/04/16/aws-london-summit-notes/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Summit London 2015 ## Keynote
There were about three thousand people at the summit. I chatted to a few people throughout the day. Their experience with AWS ranged from moderate use through to just being at the evaluation stage.
The keynote highlighted AWS&amp;rsquo;s approach of wanting to put the customer in control, and to remove all unnecessary work from the customer in terms of managing IT.
AWS has grown enormously, they are estimated to have five times the compute power on hand than all other cloud providers combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>looking for ideas for our wikimania talk on open scholarship tools</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2014/07/29/wikimania-openscholarship-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2014/07/29/wikimania-openscholarship-preview/</guid>
      <description>Inspired somewhat by the aweome http://sciencetoolbox.org, along with Martin Fenner, we proposed a session for the upcoming Wikimania conference. We will be talking about Open Scholarship Tools on Sunday the 10th of August at 9:30 am. In our outline for our talk we have decided to possibly think about:
 CrossRef API (and possibly also the DataCite and ORCID APIs) Pandoc Rstudio Zotero iPython Notebook Plotly Datawrapper  What do you think we should try to cover in our 30 minute slot?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpotOn day 2.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2012/11/12/spoton-solo12-day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2012/11/12/spoton-solo12-day2/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was awesome, let&amp;rsquo;s see how today goes. I was watching from afar, as my wife attended, and now I&amp;rsquo;m here for the afternoon sessions.
sessions:  Ben Goldacre publishing data, what&amp;rsquo;s in it for researchers?  now on to the sessions!
[Incentivising Open Access][ioa].(top) Nice panel, you can see the list of the panel on the site homepage, I&amp;rsquo;ll again, mostly focus on the trend of the discussion.
What do researchers get credit for?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpotOn day 1.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2012/11/11/spoton-solo12-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2012/11/11/spoton-solo12-day1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll keep a partial, live-idsh blog going during the day. I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to these things, I think, since about 2008. I really like these meetings. I&amp;rsquo;m going to probably keep these notes pretty lightweight.
sessions:  Ben Goldacre Kamila  Session on whether science journalism will be replaced Altmetric track  now on to the sessions!
Ben Goldacre - opening keynote, on data. .(top) Ben is talking about the issues that arise when you place a lot of data in one place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last minute changes to our solo12journals line up.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2012/11/10/last-minute-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2012/11/10/last-minute-changes/</guid>
      <description>* {margin:0; padding:0} body {font:11px/1.5 Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; background:#FFF} #text {margin:50px auto; width:500px} .hotspot {color:#900; padding-bottom:1px; border-bottom:1px dotted #900; cursor:pointer} #tt {position:absolute; display:block; background:url(images/tt_left.gif) top left no-repeat} #tttop {display:block; height:5px; margin-left:5px; background:url(images/tt_top.gif) top right no-repeat; overflow:hidden} #ttcont {display:block; padding:2px 12px 3px 7px; margin-left:5px; background:#666; color:#FFF} #ttbot {display:block; height:5px; margin-left:5px; background:url(images/tt_bottom.gif) top right no-repeat; overflow:hidden}  I&#39;m really excited about the session that we will be running at SpotOn London in just two days time!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancelled :( Drinks with Chris Wiggins.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2010/12/20/drinks-with-chris-wiggins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2010/12/20/drinks-with-chris-wiggins/</guid>
      <description>Due to flight cancellations out of NY, Chris won&amp;rsquo;t be making it over to this side of the pond, so sadly we will be calling the event off.London is a great city to live in if you are interested in technology. It has to be one of the best cities in the world for people working on the interface between science, tech and te web. Tonight I&amp;rsquo;ll be going to the awesome Same As Christmass Quiz, and tomorrow night Chris Wiggins will be passing through from New York, and there will be a chance to meet up with him for a pint and a chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Knowledge Organisation on the Web, a one day conference.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2010/09/14/linked-data-london-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2010/09/14/linked-data-london-meeting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m attending this event today, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep some notes as the day progresses. There are a couple of oddities about the event:
 No Coffee. That&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a pity No power outlets in the conference room. Not many conferences have that, but one would think that it is a no brainer, especially for any meeting about the web, and in particular linked data. To add to that, there also seems to be no public wifi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liam dropping by london</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/liam-dropping-by-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/liam-dropping-by-london/</guid>
      <description>    10072007136    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>