<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review - Tiamat’s wrath - book nine of the expanse series.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2019/09/10/book_review_-_tiamats_wrath_-_book_nine_of_the_expanse_series._/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2019/09/10/book_review_-_tiamats_wrath_-_book_nine_of_the_expanse_series._/</guid>
      <description>This book review is really only for people who have been reading all of the expanse book series. If you have not then there are some spoilers in here.
I finished this over my summer holiday, and it was a ton of fun.
I noted that In the first few books of the series when the action was contained within the solar system a lot of book time was taken up describing the time it took to travel around the solar system, and the intricacies if the orbital mechanics that went into that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today at lunch duplicators and instantiators</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/today-at-lunch-duplicators-and-instantiators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/today-at-lunch-duplicators-and-instantiators/</guid>
      <description>I work at a pretty innovative place and the discussions that we have atlunch time are pretty mind bending. The last time I can recall having somany interesting discussions over lunch and breaks was way back when I wasin my first undergraduate degree, but the topics of conversation that tendto come up at my current place of employment are really worth trying torecord.
Today we started off having a couple of split conversation, Euan describingchatting to Martha at Sci-Foo and Euan and I talking about Euler, as you do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>