<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Limiting “Software Infant mortality” rate — decoding GO-JEK’s Deployment Checklist</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/06/21/limiting_software_infant_mortality_rate__decoding_go-jeks_deployment_checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/06/21/limiting_software_infant_mortality_rate__decoding_go-jeks_deployment_checklist/</guid>
      <description>A great example of using a &amp;ldquo;flight plan checklist&amp;rdquo; to reduce risk in software development.
https://blog.gojekengineering.com/limiting-software-infant-mortality-rate-decoding-gojek-deployment-checklist-1c6cc3e28df</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Visualize an XML Sitemap Using Python - Ayima</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/06/06/how_to_visualize_an_xml_sitemap_using_python_-_ayima/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/06/06/how_to_visualize_an_xml_sitemap_using_python_-_ayima/</guid>
      <description>This looks like a great way to quickly get an overview of your site architecture, a vital step when thinking about wide spread changes.
https://www.ayima.com/blog/how-to-visualize-an-xml-sitemap-using-python.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunting for structure in nested JSON with python just got a whole lot easier</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/05/11/hunting_for_structure_in_nested_json_with_python_just_got_a_whole_lot_easier_/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/05/11/hunting_for_structure_in_nested_json_with_python_just_got_a_whole_lot_easier_/</guid>
      <description>A very common python task that I find myself stumbling over repeatedly is trying to get the syntax right to address or retrieve a specific value to a key in a dented JSON document, in particular if that key is some way down the tree.
I’ve just found the library https://github.com/mahmoud/glom which is written up really nicely here: https://sedimental.org/glom_restructured_data.html
Before looking at this modele in detail I had thought that I could pass a reference to a key to glom without specifying its location fully in the structure of the input file, but after looking at this for a moment it became clear that this is not what it does, but rather is good at helping to remap nested data structures into new structures, and accessing the data you want via path like queries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse DOI lookups with Crossref</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/01/10/crossref-reverse-lookups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/01/10/crossref-reverse-lookups/</guid>
      <description>Today I had a need to think about how to do a reverse lookup of a formatted citation to find a DOI.
@CrossrefOrg helped out and pointed me to the reverse api endpoint. It workes like this:
http://api.crossref.org/reverse
Created a json payload file “citation.json” formatted as follows:
[ &amp;#34;	Curtis, J. R., Wenrich, M. D., Carline, J. D., Shannon, S. E., Ambrozy, D. M., &amp;amp; Ramsey, P. G. (2001). Understanding physicians’ skills at providing end-of-life care: Perspectives of patients, families, and health care workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If programming is magic, then the old languages are strong</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/if-programming-is-magic-then-the-old-languages-are-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/if-programming-is-magic-then-the-old-languages-are-strong/</guid>
      <description>The similarity between magic and programming is never more apparent thanwhen you sit down and watch someone who is truly good on the command line.By virtue of having secret knowledge they can quickly accomplish theapparently impossible. If you start out in the unix world you begin bylearning some simple incantations such as &#39;cd&#39;, &#39;ls&#39; and &#39;top&#39; and &#39;kill&#39;.If you persevere with the art eventually you may master the hidden runesthat bring &#39;sed&#39; and &#39;awk&#39; to life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>