<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scifi on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/scifi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scifi on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/scifi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review - Tiamat’s wrath - book nine of the expanse series.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2019/09/10/book_review_-_tiamats_wrath_-_book_nine_of_the_expanse_series._/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2019/09/10/book_review_-_tiamats_wrath_-_book_nine_of_the_expanse_series._/</guid>
      <description>This book review is really only for people who have been reading all of the expanse book series. If you have not then there are some spoilers in here.
I finished this over my summer holiday, and it was a ton of fun.
I noted that In the first few books of the series when the action was contained within the solar system a lot of book time was taken up describing the time it took to travel around the solar system, and the intricacies if the orbital mechanics that went into that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three body problem.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2019/09/10/the_three_body_problem._/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2019/09/10/the_three_body_problem._/</guid>
      <description>I’ve just zipped through this book in what feels like about a week, but was probably a bit longer.
I didn’t like it.
The book sets up engagement with a computer game as a key plot driver, along with specific behaviours of an alien civilisation. Both of these are central to the driver of the book and in both cases I wasn’t able to believe what was happening.
They lacked internal consistency and plausibility, in particular the plot device of unpacking a proton and accessing higher dimensional spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>