<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Zoo - Pretrained deep learning models for transfer learning, educational purposes, and more</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/06/21/model_zoo_-_pretrained_deep_learning_models_for_transfer_learning_educational_purposes_and_more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/06/21/model_zoo_-_pretrained_deep_learning_models_for_transfer_learning_educational_purposes_and_more/</guid>
      <description>This looks like an interesting corpus of machine learning models. One thing I&amp;rsquo;d not really thought about before is that we will now need to start thinking about how to publish the actual models that are used in scholarly research. Some of the models on this site provide ways to reference the work (e.g. https://modelzoo.co/model/image-to-image-translation-with-conditional-adversarial-networks).
https://modelzoo.co/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI and discovery tools</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/04/27/ai_and_discovery_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/04/27/ai_and_discovery_tools/</guid>
      <description>I got asked to contribute an answer to an upcoming feature looking at trends in scholarly discovery.
There are four questions and I’ve been asked to think about an answer to the last of these four.
 In a sentence or two, please tell us what you understand is meant by &amp;lsquo;discovery&amp;rsquo;?
For a researcher, how has the discovery experience developed in recent years?
How can researchers decide which tools are going to do the right job for them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The robots are coming, the promise and perils of AI - questions</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/11/09/the_robots_are_coming_the_promise_and_perils_of_ai_-_questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/11/09/the_robots_are_coming_the_promise_and_perils_of_ai_-_questions/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m at the Charleston conference, my first time, and we had a panel discussion this morning talking about AI.
On the panel were:
Heather Staines Director of Partnerships, Hypothes.is
Peter Brantley Director of Online Strategy, UC Davis
Elizabeth Caley Chief of Staff, Meta, Chan Zuckerberg Initiative
Ruth Pickering Co-founder and Chief Strategy Officer, Yewno
and myself. It was a pleasure to be on a panel with these amazing people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>aws london summit notes</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2015/04/16/aws-london-summit-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2015/04/16/aws-london-summit-notes/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Summit London 2015 ## Keynote
There were about three thousand people at the summit. I chatted to a few people throughout the day. Their experience with AWS ranged from moderate use through to just being at the evaluation stage.
The keynote highlighted AWS&amp;rsquo;s approach of wanting to put the customer in control, and to remove all unnecessary work from the customer in terms of managing IT.
AWS has grown enormously, they are estimated to have five times the compute power on hand than all other cloud providers combined.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>