<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sage on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/sage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sage on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/sage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m hiring a product manager</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/07/20/im-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/07/20/im-hiring/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;m hiring a product manager. We are working on developing new green field products. We have a small, really fun team, and we are using a lot of lean tools to try to get to product-market fit with relativly low risk.
To apply submit a CV using our [hiring portal](https://uk.sagepub.com/en-gb/eur/sage-vacancies].
Here are some more details about the role:
What we are doing SAGE is innovating around how we might support social science researchers engaging with big data and new technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IC2s2 2017, conference preview</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/07/10/ic2s2-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/07/10/ic2s2-preview/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m about to head to Köln for the International Conference on Computational Social Science (IC2S2) and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty excited for a whole bunch of reasons.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated by network science, and the potential application of techniques from that science to the rest of research, for quite a while, but generally this has been an interest that I have entertained from a distance.
I had the pleasure of attending an early instance of the NetSci conference series back in 2008, and even contributed to a working paper looking at the implications of the intersection between social data and network algorithms (Mining for Social Serendipity), however the academic track has not been my track at all, and with one thing or another this was a community that my career moved me away from for some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello SAGE!</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2016/12/15/hello-sage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2016/12/15/hello-sage/</guid>
      <description>Hello SAGE! I joined SAGE at the start of September. Hello SAGE!! Here I outline some of my initial impressions.
First up, I&amp;rsquo;ve been really delighted to meet so many great people at SAGE. I&amp;rsquo;ve received great support from everyone in the company. I generally find publishing folk to be very friendly. This is a friendly industry, working on the fabric of knowledge, knowing that your work can help to make a difference, trying to make the work of academics a bit easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scholarly comms product meetup - V2 - announcement</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/04/18/scholarly_comms_product_meetup_-_v2_-_announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/04/18/scholarly_comms_product_meetup_-_v2_-_announcement/</guid>
      <description>How can I ensure that changes are reflected in the Atom editor?
Back in November we ran the first scholarly comms meetup with a focus on product management. There are lots of great meet ups out there for people who work in scholarly comms, but we felt that there might be an unscratched need to have a meeting where the focus was not explicitly on community building, or on new technologies, or on public outreach, or on new trends and technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>