<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>https://partiallyattended.com/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://partiallyattended.com/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What do we mean when we talk about Big Data?</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2016/12/15/what-is-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2016/12/15/what-is-big-data/</guid>
      <description>What do we mean when we talk about Big Data?
The following blog post about this article provides the following definition of big data:
 “High volume data that frequently combines highly structured administrative data actively collected by public sector organisations with continuously and automatically collected structured and unstructured real-time data that are often passively created by public and private entities through their internet.”
 The article is behind a paywall, but the blog is pretty clearly laid out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Data, first impressions</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2016/12/08/quick-review-covalent-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2016/12/08/quick-review-covalent-data/</guid>
      <description>Covalent Data is a tool to search over research topics. It seems to have the following features:
 Is a DB of grants, papers, people and institutions.
 claims to use machine learning to tie these entities together.
 search results don’t seem to have a way to be exported, so for example though the grant awards results do list the amount of each grant, to get a total amount against a search term, you would need to do the work of extracting each data point manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>academic ghost towns, Google scholar and Mendeley</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2012/07/17/academic-ghost-towns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2012/07/17/academic-ghost-towns/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m on a mission to clear out my instapapper backlocg, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to be blogging olds rather than news. There was a nice piece in the Atlantic last month talking about how Google could provide a better social experience by activating it&amp;rsquo;s latent networks, rather than mimicking facebook.
 But think about Scholar as a latent social network. Each paper contains its own social network that Google already crawls. Every bibliography is filled with other social networks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>