<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>/categories/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>aws london summit notes</title>
      <link>/2015/04/16/aws-london-summit-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/04/16/aws-london-summit-notes/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Web Summit London 2015 ## Keynote
There were about three thousand people at the summit. I chatted to a few people throughout the day. Their experience with AWS ranged from moderate use through to just being at the evaluation stage.
The keynote highlighted AWS&amp;rsquo;s approach of wanting to put the customer in control, and to remove all unnecessary work from the customer in terms of managing IT.
AWS has grown enormously, they are estimated to have five times the compute power on hand than all other cloud providers combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Vagrant, Librarian-Chef and Vagrant aws plugins on OSX Mavericks.</title>
      <link>/2013/11/19/osx-mavericks-vagrant-librarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/19/osx-mavericks-vagrant-librarian/</guid>
      <description>I have a new macbook pro. I want to install vagrant, chef and librarian, with the vagrant-aws plugins. I&amp;rsquo;m working on OSX Mavericks, and I want to get as clean an install as possible. For the most part I am also using the fish shell. This is what I&amp;rsquo;ve just run through over the last 20 minutes.
 Install command line tools from the terminal
$ xcode-select --install  Next we are going to install homebrew, with homebrew we will install rvm and with rvm we will install ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>