<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Barcamp on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/barcamp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Barcamp on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/barcamp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BarCamp Cambridge - James Smith talking about Ensemble, head of the internet team for Ensemble</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge---james-smith-talking-about-ensemble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge---james-smith-talking-about-ensemble/</guid>
      <description>Ensemble came out of the human genome project about 8 years ago to preventcommercialization of genomic data.
the idea was to have an open source human genome
companies would have to do some work before they could make money off ofsequences.
the ensemble projects takes the raw data from the genes and adds other datato this, such as reference data from other experiments
there is enemble codeand there is the data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BarCamp Cambridge - James talking about HTML5</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge---james-talking-about-html5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge---james-talking-about-html5/</guid>
      <description>James is just an interested bysander on the HTML 5 mailing list, hey, it&#39;s abarcamp
html5 is th enew verison of html
applemozillaoperaanyone who joins the mailing list
and
w3c (which means MS, which means this is going to work in IE)
if you have ideas, then you can joing hte mailing list and put ideasforwards for the specification
why should we?
lots of information is locked up in HTML, not XML, not SVGL</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BarCamp Cambridge - teacking computers to understand text, Peter Corbett</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge---teacking-computers-to-understand-text-peter-corbett/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge---teacking-computers-to-understand-text-peter-corbett/</guid>
      <description>a desk at the computer lab and at the chemistry lab.
computationl lingustic chemistryauto-detect language in chemistry papers to try to recognics chemical andmarkup.
suppliment the mark-up from publishers.
can draw the chemical and annotating them overlayed over the paper
some problems are that there can be new names in papers,comapct names, include extra hyphens, this program can deal with these kindsof things.
also can use systematics parsing.
this is the core technology, you can do things like search for alkloids inyour paper, or document dump</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BarCamp Cambridge Jeff Fates, Drupal</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge-jeff-fates-drupal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge-jeff-fates-drupal/</guid>
      <description>OS CMS systems beat the crap out of the free ones for what you get for your money, including support.
If you have a budget then you can get in touch with the authors of the OS systems easily
the only thing they sometimes don&#39;t win on is polish
it is someone&#39;s job to look at each piece and make sure that it is slick
Drupal is free, It upgrades about twice&amp;#160; a year, one major one minor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BarCamp Cambridge, ARM microcontroler</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge-arm-microcontroler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge-arm-microcontroler/</guid>
      <description>ARM microcontroler dev guy.
hard to use these processors, whanted to make something like this availableto normal peoplewant internet bluetooth connected devices
so they built something
he just plugged in a microcontoler with a wireless sensorhis machine things that it&#39;s a flash drive
he dregged over a binarythe device started blinking, this is the hello world of hardware hacking,cool
what can you do now? well cool stuff obviously!
the other cool thing is that there is a compiler on a websiteso you can talk about things in the context that people imagine themthis is built on top of c++</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BarCamp Cambridge, Tom Morris, Semantic Web for hackers</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge-tom-morris-semantic-web-for-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge-tom-morris-semantic-web-for-hackers/</guid>
      <description>what&#39;s cool about microformats web?
is it the stickers?the t-shirtsthe community process
urlb.at/2f
personal information disastertravel airlines don&#39;t talk to railroads
 microformats say, what problem does it solve?
 perhaps there is no problem at all
what problem does blogging solve?Twitter for christ&#39;s sake?
no one knows what they do until they are popular
e.g. yahoo pipes is not practical yetit is a user experience nightmareand it doesn&#39;t have a clear defined purpose</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>live blogging from BarCamp Cambridge,</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/live-blogging-from-barcamp-cambridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/live-blogging-from-barcamp-cambridge/</guid>
      <description> I am at Bar Camp Cambridge,
We have had the three word introductions and are just running through themorning talks now. It&#39;s pretty cool.
The coffee is good, and cookies are great.
Let&#39;s see how the day goes.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>live blogging from BarCamp Cambridge, Laura James</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/live-blogging-from-barcamp-cambridge-laura-james/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/live-blogging-from-barcamp-cambridge-laura-james/</guid>
      <description>Laura JamesAlert Me.Com
might get too corporate.
trying to do the internet of things, internet access to small devicesthey are implimetning today, and will be shipping later this year.comes from R&amp;amp;D, but working in a shipping
they are going to ship a home security system, but they are actuallybuilding a platofrmthat can connect anything that does not require full audio and video
using a mesh network that connect to a hub using a &#39;zigby&#39;output can be things like a lamp that has a color dependant state</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>live blogging from BarCamp Cambridge, Matt&#39;s discussion</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/live-blogging-from-barcamp-cambridge-matts-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/live-blogging-from-barcamp-cambridge-matts-discussion/</guid>
      <description>  discussionQ Gridle is raised along with RDFa if you don&#39;t like the way that the xslt is workin you can make your own.however most domain exprts can&#39;t write xslt
if you just let the domain experts create microformats you may leave theontologicaldefinitions to people who are creating the xslt
AG says that there may be two different problems, address to addressbookfrom page vs data harvesting
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>live blogging from BarCamp Cambridge, Matt&#39;s talk</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/live-blogging-from-barcamp-cambridge-matts-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/live-blogging-from-barcamp-cambridge-matts-talk/</guid>
      <description>Matt talking about semanitic web for science, an introductionXML, URI, namespaces, RDL OWL,standards are often argued about but it;s just XML
we are supposed to be able to publish semantis data easily,at the moment it&#39;s not just an extension but a whole other world,people won&#39;t learn sapqrl
Matt believes that we can get the benifits of semantic now, but withoutin any case, it&#39;s hard to get funding
should consider semantic web, rather than Semantic Web,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>