<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coasp on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/coasp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coasp on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/coasp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature, Whiskey and me</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/10/07/nature-whiskey-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/10/07/nature-whiskey-and-me/</guid>
      <description>In my earlier post on Megajournals I hinted that I felt that there could be a future in which this business model provided sufficient funds to allow a publishing house like NPG to make it&amp;rsquo;s flagship journal Nature an open access journal.
This topic came up late one evening at coasp and I ended up making a bet with Matias Piipari. I bet that within 10 years Nature would become a fully open access journal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hindawi have an awesome reviewing system.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/10/06/hindawi-reviewing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/10/06/hindawi-reviewing/</guid>
      <description>Hindawi publishers is a really interesting outfit. They are an open access only publisher based in Egypt. They combing a fantastic use of technology with the ability to afford a large amount of human curation over the data that they use to streamline their publication and reviewing systems.
One of their publishing vehicles is called the International Scholarly Research Network and at the recent coasp conference Paul Peters gave an overview of how their peer review system works, I think it&amp;rsquo;s genius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Megajournals</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/10/03/megajournals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/10/03/megajournals/</guid>
      <description>The idea of megajournals had not really formalised in my head before, but at the COASP meeting the talk was all about &amp;ldquo;Megajournals&amp;rdquo;. [PLoSOne][plosone] is the archetype for this kind of journal, and it had not really struck me before as a huge revolution in the publishing industry, but after listening to a couple of days worth of talks on the topic I&amp;rsquo;m convincible.
Megajournals are so called because they are structured to be able to publish many more articles than has been the normal practice with traditional journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rude health of Open Access Publishing.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/10/03/coasp-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2011/10/03/coasp-impressions/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR OA publishing is maturing with a scalable business model that all the big publishers are jumping all over. Money will be made (but less than before), and more content will be more open. The poor lamentable nay-sayers who carp on unheard in the darkness will be forgotten, and their Cassandra-like predictions will fade to be recalled as little more than the mutterings of fools (OK, that last bit is probably opinion).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>