<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Product Management on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/product-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Product Management on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/product-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy in a Lean Enterprise - lean value tree.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/06/07/strategy_in_a_lean_enterprise_-_lean_value_tree./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/06/07/strategy_in_a_lean_enterprise_-_lean_value_tree./</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with lean value tree as a framework for some time now, but there are few online resources about this. The linked presentation does a great job of giving an overview of the tool. In particular I like how they call out the need to describe the promise of value to the customer, something that we could definitely do more of.
Another presentation on the same topic is this one: https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m hiring a product manager</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/07/20/im-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/07/20/im-hiring/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;m hiring a product manager. We are working on developing new green field products. We have a small, really fun team, and we are using a lot of lean tools to try to get to product-market fit with relativly low risk.
To apply submit a CV using our [hiring portal](https://uk.sagepub.com/en-gb/eur/sage-vacancies].
Here are some more details about the role:
What we are doing SAGE is innovating around how we might support social science researchers engaging with big data and new technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about product management</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2015/03/05/thoughts-on-product-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2015/03/05/thoughts-on-product-management/</guid>
      <description>I moved into digital product management in 2007. I had no formal training, and for much of the last eight years I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning on the job. There are a huge number of resources out there, great lectures, books, conferences, blog posts. In this short post I just want to reflect a bit on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned on this topic through direct personal experience. I continue to learn, and my thinking continues to evolve, so this post is more of a look back, than a look to the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>