<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goals on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>https://partiallyattended.com/categories/goals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goals on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://partiallyattended.com/categories/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing goals update 1, 2014</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2014/03/30/q1-climbing-goals-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2014/03/30/q1-climbing-goals-update/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a large post at the start of this year reviewing my climbing goals over previous years, and laying out my goals for 2014. A key modification for me in 2014 is changing to a strategy where I set goals quarterly, rather than yearly. Let&amp;rsquo;s review Q1.
Goals for q1 2014  try at least 12 routes of 6c or harder
I managed to try exactly 12 routes of 6c in the last 12 weeks, and my last try yielded success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of climbing goals, goals for 2014</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2014/01/18/climbing-review-2013-goals-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2014/01/18/climbing-review-2013-goals-2014/</guid>
      <description>For the last couple of years I have done an end of year review of my climbing over the previous year, and set myself some goals for the coming year. Rather than doing exactly the same thing this time, I thought it would be good to look back at several of these reviews over the past couple of years, look at the data on my climbing, and see if I could discover any insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing Goals 2012, review 2011</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2012/01/08/climbing-goals-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2012/01/08/climbing-goals-2012/</guid>
      <description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote up my climbing goals for 2010, and I totally missed doing this for last year, so as we ease our way into 2012 it&amp;rsquo;s high time that I do the same again.
The key goals for 2010 were:
 redpoint fr 7a boulder V5 trad E1 some trips to do some trad climbing  Well, since then I achieved the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing Goals 2010, review 2009.</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2010/01/04/climbing-goals-2010-review-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2010/01/04/climbing-goals-2010-review-2009/</guid>
      <description>Looking back at my goals for 2009, I&#39;ve not done very well, however my current level of fitness is pretty good, so I think 2010 is going to be a good year.
The main factors in holding back my climbing in 2009 were taking a few months off to get married and not being able to rent a car. Getting married was absolutely worth it, and the level of organisation and stability I have in my life now due to being married will only help in the long run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m setting up this blog</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2009/04/13/why-im-setting-up-this-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2009/04/13/why-im-setting-up-this-blog/</guid>
      <description>Right, well, I&#39;m pretty interested in graph theory. I work in publishing for the journal Nature on new web products, and I need a focussed way of getting my thoughts together on a range of topics that touch on science. I wanted a space that was more focussed than my personal blog.
I have a few specific aims for this blog. Get some of my thoughts on publishing, science and the philosophy of science out of my head and into an archived public space</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Climbing Goals for 2008.</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2008/12/23/review-of-climbing-goals-for-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2008/12/23/review-of-climbing-goals-for-2008/</guid>
      <description>Back in January I set myself some goals for my climbing in 2008. The results at the end of the year were mixed, which means that I succeeded with some of my goals and patently failed with others. The was:
* Onsight Grit E2
* Redpoint f6c+
* 10 weekende+ trips in UK
* 5 red problems in a day in font
* 80 kg weight
* build climbing wall</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>