<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Training on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/training/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Training on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer replaces workers, workers ty to turn into data scientists.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/05/16/computer_replaces_workers_workers_ty_to_turn_into_data_scientists._/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/05/16/computer_replaces_workers_workers_ty_to_turn_into_data_scientists._/</guid>
      <description>http://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-tn-automation-training-20180504-story.html
The headline is a bit click-baitey. I think the big takeaway from this article is that there is a significant shift in how companies are doing training with the advent of online learning. Unsurprising, but hopefully good news for efforts like sage campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing outlook for 2015</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2015/02/11/climbing-update-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2015/02/11/climbing-update-2015/</guid>
      <description>Last year I hit on the best way to set climbing goals (this was after many years of failing to hit my goals). The best way to do it was to set very short term goals, not ones for the end of the year, but rather quarter by quarter, and modify and update those goals as I went. In addition, I found that focussing not on outcomes, but on process, also helped a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing goals update 1, 2014</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2014/03/30/q1-climbing-goals-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2014/03/30/q1-climbing-goals-update/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a large post at the start of this year reviewing my climbing goals over previous years, and laying out my goals for 2014. A key modification for me in 2014 is changing to a strategy where I set goals quarterly, rather than yearly. Let&amp;rsquo;s review Q1.
Goals for q1 2014  try at least 12 routes of 6c or harder
I managed to try exactly 12 routes of 6c in the last 12 weeks, and my last try yielded success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing review of 2012, goals 2013.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2013/03/24/climbing-review-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2013/03/24/climbing-review-2012/</guid>
      <description>212 climbing review. OK, time to review the year. I wrote out some goals at the start of last year.
Goals for 2012 were  remain injury free (not done) significantly reduce the amount of alcohol that I consume (done) fall off at least 10 routes of 6c or harder/month (not done) redpoint 7a, but don&amp;rsquo;t stop trying harder things (not done) get three campus board sessions or power hand sessions into my training per month (done)  My training diary from 2011 looked like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Font, Spring 2011, quick report</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2013/03/24/font-spring-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2013/03/24/font-spring-2011/</guid>
      <description>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been almost a week since I got back from Fontainbleau. It was, as usual, a magical trip. Were took advantage of the row of bank holidays to get in a nice long spell in the forest without having to take too much time off work.
I&amp;rsquo;d been training like a fair old bastard in order to get fit for Marie Rose, but in the end a couple of injuries stopped me going near the route, which was a pity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Font, Spring 2013, preview</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2013/03/24/font-spring-2013-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2013/03/24/font-spring-2013-preview/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m about to head to Fontainbleau for another short climbing trip. I&amp;rsquo;ve been going there since 2003, this will be my 10th anniversary of going to font.
The first time I went there I brought a lot of expectations with me. I was climbing pretty well and I fully expected that I should be able to run up problems of about font 6a. I think I fell off of that first 3a 6 times before I got it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climbing Goals 2010, review 2009.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2010/01/04/climbing-goals-2010-review-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2010/01/04/climbing-goals-2010-review-2009/</guid>
      <description>Looking back at my goals for 2009, I&#39;ve not done very well, however my current level of fitness is pretty good, so I think 2010 is going to be a good year.
The main factors in holding back my climbing in 2009 were taking a few months off to get married and not being able to rent a car. Getting married was absolutely worth it, and the level of organisation and stability I have in my life now due to being married will only help in the long run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Climbing Goals for 2008.</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/12/23/review-of-climbing-goals-for-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/12/23/review-of-climbing-goals-for-2008/</guid>
      <description>Back in January I set myself some goals for my climbing in 2008. The results at the end of the year were mixed, which means that I succeeded with some of my goals and patently failed with others. The was:
* Onsight Grit E2
* Redpoint f6c+
* 10 weekende+ trips in UK
* 5 red problems in a day in font
* 80 kg weight
* build climbing wall</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting motivated for climbing</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/getting-motivated-for-climbing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2008/07/14/getting-motivated-for-climbing/</guid>
      <description>A good friend of mine has just hit the 8a mark in climbing. Dave is a greatclimber, and a really nice guy, but what really blew me away is that hisfiancee Caroline led 7b on her first sports climbing trip.
One thing know about both of them is that they do a lot of running,something like 10 - 15 miles evrey morning.
If this isn&#39;t motivation for me to pick up running then I don&#39;t know whatis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>