<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rss on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>/categories/rss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rss on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/rss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BarCamp Cambridge - James Smith talking about Ensemble, head of the internet team for Ensemble</title>
      <link>/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge---james-smith-talking-about-ensemble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge---james-smith-talking-about-ensemble/</guid>
      <description>Ensemble came out of the human genome project about 8 years ago to preventcommercialization of genomic data.
the idea was to have an open source human genome
companies would have to do some work before they could make money off ofsequences.
the ensemble projects takes the raw data from the genes and adds other datato this, such as reference data from other experiments
there is enemble codeand there is the data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BarCamp Cambridge, Tom Morris, Semantic Web for hackers</title>
      <link>/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge-tom-morris-semantic-web-for-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/07/14/barcamp-cambridge-tom-morris-semantic-web-for-hackers/</guid>
      <description>what&#39;s cool about microformats web?
is it the stickers?the t-shirtsthe community process
urlb.at/2f
personal information disastertravel airlines don&#39;t talk to railroads
 microformats say, what problem does it solve?
 perhaps there is no problem at all
what problem does blogging solve?Twitter for christ&#39;s sake?
no one knows what they do until they are popular
e.g. yahoo pipes is not practical yetit is a user experience nightmareand it doesn&#39;t have a clear defined purpose</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sometimes, just sometimes a piece of news makes me smile</title>
      <link>/2008/07/14/sometimes-just-sometimes-a-piece-of-news-makes-me-smile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/07/14/sometimes-just-sometimes-a-piece-of-news-makes-me-smile/</guid>
      <description> From the Guardian today, a group of ultra-right wing MEP&#39;s were unable toform a group within the European Parliament owing to internal xenophobia.
http://www.guardian.co.uk/farright/story/0,,2211167,00.html?gusrc=rss&amp;amp;feed=12
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>