<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chef on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>https://partiallyattended.com/categories/chef/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chef on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://partiallyattended.com/categories/chef/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Vagrant, Librarian-Chef and Vagrant aws plugins on OSX Mavericks.</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2013/11/19/osx-mavericks-vagrant-librarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2013/11/19/osx-mavericks-vagrant-librarian/</guid>
      <description>I have a new macbook pro. I want to install vagrant, chef and librarian, with the vagrant-aws plugins. I&amp;rsquo;m working on OSX Mavericks, and I want to get as clean an install as possible. For the most part I am also using the fish shell. This is what I&amp;rsquo;ve just run through over the last 20 minutes.
 Install command line tools from the terminal
$ xcode-select --install  Next we are going to install homebrew, with homebrew we will install rvm and with rvm we will install ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicating better, moving from virtualenv to vagrant/Chef</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2013/04/23/chef-vagrant-over-virutalenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2013/04/23/chef-vagrant-over-virutalenv/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using virtualenv for a while, but in the past few months, since taking up the role of head of technology for eLife, I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving much more thought about how to build scalable development environments.
Ever since I was managing connotea, one of the biggest pains has been configuration management. I seem to have spent almost more time on configuring environments than on actually doing any development work (disclaimer, I don&amp;rsquo;t actually do much coding, I usually do more product management, but it&amp;rsquo;s really useful to know the development pain points).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>