<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>computational socical science on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/computational-socical-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in computational socical science on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/computational-socical-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>choice magazine podcast Questions</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/05/04/choice_magazine_podcast_questions_/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2018/05/04/choice_magazine_podcast_questions_/</guid>
      <description>This week I was interviewed for the ALA choice podcast, a podcast that the that is
 a weekly program featuring in-depth conversations about contemporary trends, best practices, and case studies important to academic librarians. Hosted by Bill Mickey, the Editorial Director at Choice
 The topic was about trends in big data and the role of the library, and it was really fun to participate in, and the panel I was on included Caroline Muglia from the University of Southern California Libraries as well as Andy Rutkowski and Eimmy Karina Solis from USC libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IC2s2 Tuesday Afternoon Keynotes</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/07/11/ic2s2_tuesday_afternoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2017/07/11/ic2s2_tuesday_afternoon/</guid>
      <description>IC2s2 Tuesday afternoon  Dashun Wang - Predictive Signals Behind Success Dashun starts by talking about weather predictions, natural phenomena can be observed, modelled and predicted. Can success be measured modelled and predicted? Obviously Dashun thinks so, and we are gong to be looking at the result of a number of studies in this talk.
Science of Science Aim is to build on top of the work of others, but add to it the massive data that we now have access to, along with the tools that we have developed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>