<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>http://partiallyattended.com/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://partiallyattended.com/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello SAGE!</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2016/12/15/hello-sage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2016/12/15/hello-sage/</guid>
      <description>Hello SAGE! I joined SAGE at the start of September. Hello SAGE!! Here I outline some of my initial impressions.
First up, I&amp;rsquo;ve been really delighted to meet so many great people at SAGE. I&amp;rsquo;ve received great support from everyone in the company. I generally find publishing folk to be very friendly. This is a friendly industry, working on the fabric of knowledge, knowing that your work can help to make a difference, trying to make the work of academics a bit easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Mendeley</title>
      <link>http://partiallyattended.com/2012/05/05/leaving-mendeley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://partiallyattended.com/2012/05/05/leaving-mendeley/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m starting to draft this post on the train on the commute to my new job at eLife. After almost two years I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the decision to move on from Mendeley. They were without doubt the two best and most challenging years of my career to date. Working in a start up is an amazing, frustrating, enlightening, energising and rewarding experience.
No single post can do justice to that time, and each time in the past weeks that I have drafted this post in my head it has had a slightly different timbre, so take this for what it is, a reflection in a moment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>