<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spoton on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>/categories/spoton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spoton on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/spoton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spoton13</title>
      <link>/2013/11/10/solo13-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/10/solo13-friday/</guid>
      <description>I managed to squeeze in a few hours on Friday attending the spoton conference in London. I&amp;rsquo;ve been at each one since 2008, and have had the good fortune to present something at most of them. This time I had been asked to sit in on a panel to talk about elife&amp;rsquo;s policy around media relations, but as I was flying in that morning from an editorial board meeting held in Washington it was not clear to me that I would make it in time, so the fantastic @sciencescoops (Jennifer Mitchell) represented for eLife in my place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpotOn day 2.</title>
      <link>/2012/11/12/spoton-solo12-day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/12/spoton-solo12-day2/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday was awesome, let&amp;rsquo;s see how today goes. I was watching from afar, as my wife attended, and now I&amp;rsquo;m here for the afternoon sessions.
sessions:  Ben Goldacre publishing data, what&amp;rsquo;s in it for researchers?  now on to the sessions!
[Incentivising Open Access][ioa]. (top) Nice panel, you can see the list of the panel on the site homepage, I&amp;rsquo;ll again, mostly focus on the trend of the discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpotOn day 1.</title>
      <link>/2012/11/11/spoton-solo12-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/11/spoton-solo12-day1/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll keep a partial, live-idsh blog going during the day. I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to these things, I think, since about 2008. I really like these meetings. I&amp;rsquo;m going to probably keep these notes pretty lightweight.
sessions:  Ben Goldacre Kamila  Session on whether science journalism will be replaced Altmetric track  now on to the sessions!
Ben Goldacre - opening keynote, on data. . (top) Ben is talking about the issues that arise when you place a lot of data in one place.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>