<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solo10 on Partially Attended</title>
    <link>https://partiallyattended.com/categories/solo10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solo10 on Partially Attended</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://partiallyattended.com/categories/solo10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Scientific Resources, Slides</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2010/09/07/solo10-presentation-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2010/09/07/solo10-presentation-slides/</guid>
      <description> On Friday I hosted a session at Science Online London. Michael Habibi, Richard Wallis and Chris Taylor all gave great presentations. Michael&amp;rsquo;s presentation and Richards&amp;rsquo;s presentation are both online, and when the organisers post the other talks I&amp;rsquo;ll link to Chris&amp;rsquo;s presentation too.
Michael, taking us through his talk Richard has a rapt audience Chris, getting passionate </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>science scraping with YQL</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2010/09/06/science-scraping-with-yql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2010/09/06/science-scraping-with-yql/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday at Science Online London I gave a quick tutorial on YQL, and how it might be used to mash up scientific data sets. Below I list some of the sample queries that I was playing with. Before you get started with the console have a look through the documentation. I got a lot of milage out of the part about filters and joins. The blog post by Paul Hogan on using YQL for library maships was also very helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Scientific Resources</title>
      <link>https://partiallyattended.com/2010/08/27/connecting-scientific-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://partiallyattended.com/2010/08/27/connecting-scientific-data/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to be hosting a session at science online London next weekend, I&amp;rsquo;m excited. I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in the issues of connecting scientific data for a long time. In the last six months I&amp;rsquo;ve become particularly excited about the potential of web based tool like Yahoo Query Language. I was hoping to talk a little about that, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky to get some amazing people to come and share their experiences about linking data, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to cede the floor to them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>